<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>iPOS</title>
    <description>nationally and in the Middle East. Our services includes public opinion and Surveys, market strategy and analysis, political consulting, and information systems consulting and implementation.
</description>
    <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://www.ipos.me/en/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:05:01 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:05:01 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.0.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Assessment of Iran’s February 2016 Election (Post-Election Analysis)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on the survey, conducted by iPOS on March 2016, in the view of a decisive majority of Iranians, jobs/unemployment, the economy in general, and youth problems are the issues facing the country which most deserve the consideration and action of the new parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A majority of respondents also express a preference for economic prosperity over decomcratic governance by an overwhelming margin of 71% to 18%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Below are the highlights of iPOS&#39; recent survey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Top Priorities for the New Parliament&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iranians are overwhelmingly concerned about economic issues related to jobs/unemployment and the economy compared to other issues facing the country that deserve action of the new parliament.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. In general, what should the new parliament’s top three priorities be? [Open-ended question]&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Top Priorities of the New Parliament          &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; %     &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; % Multi Response &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Jobs/Unemployment                             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 28.6% &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 53.1%            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; The Economy                                   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 25.1% &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 46.7%            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Youth                                         &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8.6%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 16.1%            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Inflation                                     &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8.3%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 15.5%            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Housing                                       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4.8%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8.9%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; General Problems of the Iranian People        &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 3.4%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6.3%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Anti-Corruption Efforts                       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 3.2%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6.0%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Foreign Policy (and Sanctions)                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 2.8%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 5.2%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Political Issues Inside the Country           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.7%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 3.2%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Security                                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.6%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 3.0%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Drugs                                         &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.5%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 2.7%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Rural Area Issues (and Agricultural Problems) &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.3%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 2.4%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Education                                     &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.2%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 2.2%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Human Rights                                  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.1%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 2.1%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Keeping Promises                              &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.9%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.6%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Healthcare                                    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.6%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.1%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Laws and Regulation (Reform and Enforcement)  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.6%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1.0%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; The Environment                               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.5%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 0.9%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Others                                        &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4.2%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 7.8%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Total                                         &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 100%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 186%             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Election Awareness&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;50% of Iranians said that they followed election news a great deal, a lot, or somewhat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. There’s a lot of talk about election news these days; how much do you personally follow such news?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart1.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart1&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Media Sources for Election News&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iran’s state radio and television was the primary source for election news among people who follow election news (43%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: What sources did you chiefly use to keep up with this sort of news? For example: newspapers, radio, television, internet, satellite, Viber and Telegram, or word of mouth? (This question was not posed to those respondents who, for the previous question, said that they do not at all follow news regarding elections. Every respondent was able to designate up to three kinds of media sources.)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Media Source for Election News &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; %    &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; % Multi Responses &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; National TV &amp;amp; Radio            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 43%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 64%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Word Of Mouth                  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 15%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 23%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Internet                       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 12%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 17%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Telegram                       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 16%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Satellite                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6%   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 9%                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Newspaper                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6%   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8%                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Leaflets, Billboard            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 5%   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8%                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Others                         &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 2%   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 3%                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Total                          &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 100% &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 148%              &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Media Sources (Satellite)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BBC Persian was the first choice of media outlet among those respondents who followed election news by way of satellite television (45%)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: What satellite channel did you chiefly use to keep up with this sort of news? (This question was posed to individuals who, in the previous question, indicated that they follow election news by way of satellite. Every respondent was able to designate up to three networks).&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Media Source - Satellite &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; %    &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; % Multi Responses &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; BBC                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 45%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 75%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Voice of America         &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 23%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 39%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Manoto TV                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 23%  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 38%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Others                   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 9%   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 16%               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Total                    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 100% &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 168%              &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Level of Freedom of the Election&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-five percent of Iranians believed that the parliamentary election was completely free and a majority of respondents, 60%, believed the election was somewhat free. Moreover, 9% registered the opinion that the election was a little free (5%) or not free at all (4%). This differs from a pre-election survey conducted by iPOS in which approximately 46% percent of Iranians believed that the parliamentary elections will be somewhat free.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: If you were to give an overall assessment, in your opinion how free was the parliamentary election as it was administered? Were people able to be freely nominated and subjected to the vote of the people? Was it completely free, free to some extent, or not free at all?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Reformists More Capable of Solving National Problems than Principalists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the survey, the largest number of Iranians (47%) did not choose to identify with a particular political group inside the country. Of those who stated that the Reformists are capable of solving problems facing the country (20%) outnumber those who believe that Principalists are capable of solving problems facing the country (9%) by 2 to 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: You may well be aware that blocs exists in the political landscape of Iran. For example, there are some groups which refer to themselves as Principalists, Reformists, or Moderates. In your opinion which one of these groups would do a better job of solving the problems the country is now facing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The largest number of respondents, 37% said that they did not know which  political group affiliation they agreed with. Among those who express a definite partisan preference, Iranians lean toward the Reformist camp by 2 to 1.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart7.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Capability of the New Parliament to Combat Corruption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nine percent of Iranians believe that the new parliament will have a greater capability to combat domestic corruption, while 32% believe that parliament will be capable of fighting corruption to an extent. Conversely, 31% believe that the new parliament will not be capable of such efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. In your opinion, how capable is the Parliament when it comes to combatting corruption and bribery? Greatly capable, capable to an extent, without much capability, or not at all capable?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart8.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Youth and Women&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many Iranians agree that politicians do not listen to the needs and ideas of young people and women.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. Please tell me how much you agree or disagree with each sentence according to the following scale: wholly agree, partially agree, entirely disagree or partially disagree? Politicians do not listen to the needs and ideas of young people.
Politicians do not listen to the needs and ideas of women.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart9.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Women’s Needs and Ideas by Gender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Female respondents are more likely than male respondents to believe that politicians neglect the needs and ideas of women to a statistically meaningful degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart10.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a marked gender gap among male and female respondents when it comes to the public’s assessment of politicians’ response to the needs and ideas of women.  45% of female respondents agree or completely agree with the statement that politicians do not listen to the needs and ideas of women, while only 28% disagree or completely disagree. Male respondents are less likely to agree with such a statement with 41% who disagree outright and 33% agree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Young People’s Needs and Ideas by Age Group&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Compared to other age groups, those who are 60 or older are least likely to agree with the statement that politicians do not listen to the needs and ideas of young people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart11.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Direction of the Country&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Iranians believe that their country is currently headed in the right direction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. In your opinion, would you say things in our country are currently heading in the right direction, or are they on the wrong track?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart12.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Iranians Support Economic Prosperity over Democracy&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iranians express a preference for economic prosperity over democratic governance by an overwhelming margin of 71% to 18%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. If you could have only one or the other, which would be more important to you: a democratic system of government or a prosperous economy?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart13.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart13&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Institutions Affected by Corruption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iranians’ evaluation of corruption rates among different institutions show that people generally deem local governing councils and the Courts and Justice Department to be the most corrupted bodies at rates of 70% and 52% respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. I’ll now read a list of few institutions. Please tell me to what extent you believe these institutions to be corrupt: very little, a little, a lot or great deal (List of Institutions: 1- The Government 2- The Parliament 3- Courts and the Justice Department 4- The Guardian Council 5- Local Governing Councils 6- The Assembly of Experts)&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart14.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart14&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The government, parliament, Guardian Council, and Assembly of Experts are deemed corrupt at rates of 35%, 30%, 19% and 14% respectively.
In light of such results, we can say that respondents were generally able to register their assessment about the level of corruption in local governing council and the courts and Justice Department. For the other four institutions, however, at least 40% of respondents either refuse to answer the question or state that they are not informed. The level of uncertainty is greatest for the Assembly of Experts, about which 54% of respondents claim no knowledge of corruption. The Guardian Council, the parliament, and the government came next in this list with 51%, 49%, and 40% respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Iranian Presence in Syria: Agreement with Security Presence, Disagreement with Financial Assistance&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most Iranians, 47%, agree with the Iranian security forces presence in Syria and 29% disagree. However, Iranians are more likely to disagree with financial assistance to the country, 43%, than to agree, 38%, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. These days there’s occasionally coverage of the Iranian security forces’ presence in Syria. I’d like to know: do you agree or disagree with this presence? A lot or a little?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart15.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart15&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q. Do you agree or disagree with the proposition that Iran should provide financial assistance to Syria?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/majles-may-2016/chart16.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart16&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews (cellphone and landline) conducted from March 11, 2016 to March 24, 2016 (excluding March 20, 2016) with a random sample of 1,077 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who currently reside in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province in Iran. Provinces have been categorized into three groups based on their human development index (HDI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is between ± 2.99 and ± 3.51 percentage points, depending on the number of respondents for each question.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nine demographic variables including gender, age, province of residence, location (urban or rural), education, language, ethnicity, religion, and residential situation have been considered in this poll. Results are weighted by gender, age, and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rates of respondent candor and reliability were appraised by experienced interviewers. 16 persons found to be lacking in these areas were removed from the sample.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from demographic variables, two ground variables (communication variables) were used to gauge respondents’ level of awareness concerning the questions taken up in this survey:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The extent to which respondents follow election news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The media outlets and sources respondents cite using to keep up with election news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elections for Iran’s Parliament (Majlis) and Assembly of Experts were held on February 26, 2016 with run-off elections occurring on April 29, 2016.  A coalition of “Moderates” according to Iranian political definition, supported by some reformists, stood to gain seats.  The coalition included President Rouhani’s supporters and two former presidents, Mr. Mohammad Khatami and Mr. Ali Akbar Hashemi and won a landslide majority of seats in Tehran in both Parliament and the Assembly of Experts.  Conversely, the Principalists and their political champions like Mr. Haddad Adel, the former speaker of the Parliament, and high-ranking religious clerics including Mr. Ali Janati, the current head of the Guardian Council, Mr. Mohammad Yazdi, chairman of the Assembly of Experts and Mr. Mesbah-Yazdi, spiritual leader of the Iranian hardliners, lost every single seat in the Tehran parliamentary contest.  Moreover, both Mr. Yazdi and Mr. Mesbah-Yazdi failed to garner enough votes in the Assembly of Experts election.  Among a total 16 seats designated for Tehran representatives to the Assembly of Experts, 15 have been filled with candidates included on the coalition list endorsed by Khatami and Rouhani.  The only other candidate who managed sufficient votes for an Assembly of Experts position was Mr. Janati, who came in at 16th place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The preliminary victory does not, however, mean that the Moderates and Reformist Coalition will enjoy a majority in the new parliament. In the lead up to the election, the Guardian Council vetoed the candidacies of 90 percent of reformist politicians.  Additionally, many of Iran’s parliamentary mechanisms work in the Principalists’ favor (especially in the case of single-member districts) due to prior partisan disqualification of many Reformist candidates for both bodies.  Of 290 total seats contested in parliament, Reformists fielded 140 candidates and supported another 90 who are not formally affiliated with Reformist ideology but share some Reformist values and goals to an extent.  This bloc includes non-Reformists, however, such as moderate conservatives represented by Ali Larijani, the current speaker of the parliament, who is tied to an informal political coalition with Rouhani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Purpose of this Survey&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPOS conducted the poll to analyze the post-election political atmosphere of Iran, including assessment of the level of freedom of the election, the functionality and affiliation of political groups, assessment of the favorability of some political figures, measuring Iranian voters’ top priorities for the new parliament’s work, and the new parliament’s capability vis a vis anti-corruption efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this survey, iPOS evaluated Iranians’ assessments of issues which they may find important, including priorities of democratic governance vs. economic prosperity, the needs and ideas of young people and women, level of corruption across different branches of government, and the Iranian government’s policy of military and financial assistance to the Syrian regime.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2016 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/05/30/parliament/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/05/30/parliament/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>2017 Presidential Elections: Rouhani 41%, Ahmadinejad 29%</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a hypothetical head-to-head matchup between the two politicians, President Rouhani garners 41% support from Iranian adults, giving him a 12-point lead over former President Mahmood Ahmadinejad’s 29% support for the next presidential election in Iran (to be held in spring of 2017.) 10% said they will not vote for either one and/or would choose another candidate. Moreover, 15% of respondents are undecided or registered options such as “I have not made my decision,” “I might not participate in the election,” etc. 5% refused to answer or said that they’re not informed about the upcoming presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Q: If Mr. Rouhani and Mr. Ahmadinejad went head-to-head in the coming presidential election in 2017, who would you vote for?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rohani-vs-ahmadinejad-16/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The same question was posed to respondents in February of 2015; at that time, Mr. Rouhani had only a modest 4-point edge, 28 % to Ahmadinejad’s 24%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rohani-vs-ahmadinejad-16/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rouhani vs. Ahmadinejad by Political Affiliation&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Reformists and Moderates are more likely to vote for Mr. Rouhani in the next presidential election, Principalists prefer Mr. Ahmadinejad in the hypothetical head-to-head matchup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rohani-vs-ahmadinejad-16/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those respondents who affiliate themselves with the Moderates are most loyal to President Rouhani in a hypothetical head-to-head matchup with former president Ahmadinejad for the 2017 presidential election: 73% of them say they will vote for him, as opposed to the 15% who prefer Mr. Ahmadinejad. Among Reformists, the level of loyalty to Mr. Rouhani is far less than that of the Moderates, though they still prefer Mr. Rouhani over Mr. Ahmadinejad by a wide margin (37-points).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ahmadinejad commands support of Principalists by an almost 19-point margin (45% to 26%). Moreover, among those who claim no affiliation, Mr. Ahmadinejad would beat Mr. Rouhani by 12 points (37% to 25%.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data analysis does demonstrate a statistically meaningful relationship between respondents’ party affiliation and their presidential vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rouhani vs. Ahmadinejad by Gender&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both male and female respondents are more likely to prefer Mr. Rouhani to Mr. Ahmadinejad to a statistically meaningful extent. Ahmadinejad’s supporters are, however, slightly more likely to be female than male.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rohani-vs-ahmadinejad-16/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rouhani vs. Ahmadinejad by Age Groups&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents 60 year of age or older favor Mr. Rouhani to Mr. Ahmadinejad at a greater frequency than other age cohorts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rohani-vs-ahmadinejad-16/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When responses are disaggregated by age, those respondents who are 60 or older are found to favor Mr. Rouhani by a 27-point margin, more than any other age cohort. In the February 2015 iPOS poll, elderly Iranians also preferred Mr. Rouhani over Mr. Ahmadinejad more than any other age group but with less pronounced a margin (11 points).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The age gap is less pronounced among younger Iranians who are of ages 30 to 44, with seven percent in Rouhani’s favor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data analysis does demonstrate a difference between these two nominees’ empirical votes, and the age groups are significantly different from each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rouhani vs. Ahmadinejad by Education&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents with university education prefer Mr. Rouhani in a head-to-head matchup by a wide margin (33 percent), while those who do not have a university education are nearly evenly split, with only a one-percent lead for Mr. Rouhani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rohani-vs-ahmadinejad-16/chart7.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rouhani vs. Ahmadinejad by Location&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents were markedly split in a statistically meaningful way by their location, with 43% of those who residing in rural areas supporting Mr. Ahmadinejad as opposed to 27% of those who support Mr. Rouhani. By contrast, just 24% of city dwellers are more likely to support Mr. Ahmadinejad while 46% of them favor Mr. Rouhani.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rohani-vs-ahmadinejad-16/chart8.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews (cellphone and landline) conducted from March 11, 2016 to March 24, 2016 (excluding March 20, 2016,) with a random sample of 1,077 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who currently reside in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province. Provinces have been categorized into three groups based on their human development index (HDI).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is between ± 3 and percentage points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nine demographic variables including gender, age, province of residence, location (urban or rural), education, language, ethnicity, religion, and residential situation have been considered in this poll. Results are weighted by gender, age, and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Rates of respondent candor and reliability were appraised by experienced interviewers. 16 persons found to be lacking in these areas were removed from the sample.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/05/25/rahoni_vs_ahmadinejad/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/05/25/rahoni_vs_ahmadinejad/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Assessment of Iran’s February 2016 Election</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Based on the poll conducted by iPOS in February 2016 regarding Iran’s 2016 Elections, more than 70% of respondents will participate. Moreover, Iranians who believe that Reformists are capable of solving problems facing the country outnumber those who believe that Principalists are so capable by 2 to 1 (19% to 9% respectively). The Reformists also enjoy a greater level of approval than Principalists (20% compared with 12% for Principalists and 5% for Moderates).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-six percent of Iranians believe that the parliamentary election will be completely free. Iranians are also split over whether the Guardian Council should vet candidates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sixty-seven percent of Iranians say that they approve of the job Mr. Rouhani is doing as president, almost 13 percentage points more than in July 2015. Eighteen percent disapprove of his performance. Only 28% of respondents approve of the job being done by parliament. A majority of Iranians (43%) disapprove of the way the parliament is doing its job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Turnout Rate: Over 70%&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the results of this poll, almost 75% of Iranians say they will definitely cast their ballot in the next parliamentary election The estimated turnout rate for the Assembly of Expert election is 73%. The last time Iran enjoyed such a massive participation in a parliamentary election was twenty years ago in 1996, with 71 percent turnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPOS anticipates that the level of participation in the 2016 election will be more than 70 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: Have you made a decision as to whether or not you’ll cast a ballot in the next parliamentary elections? Which is to say: are you going to vote or not?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: Have you made a decision as to whether or not you’ll cast a ballot in the next Assembly of Experts election? Which is to say: are you going to vote or not?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Respondents Believe that Reformists Are More Capable of Solving National Problems than Principalists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to perceptions of parties’ ability to deal successfully with problems facing the country, Reformists enjoy double the favorable opinion of Principalists (19% to 9% respectively). Five percent register favor for the Moderates, 4% say all groups should work together, and 3% believe some other third independent group is best equipped. Almost 9% of respondents believe that neither of the political parties is capable of solving such problems, and a considerable 51% express no opinion on the matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: You may be aware that there are a number of main political groups in Iran, a situation comparable to other countries in the world. For example, there are some groups which refer to themselves as Principalists, Reformists, Moderates, etc. In your opinion which one of these groups would do a better job of solving the problems the country is now facing?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of general sympathy and identification with the parties, 20% of respondents say they agree with Reformists and 12% identify with the Principalist group. Moreover, 2% say they favor both parties equally. Five percent register favor for Moderates, 6% name various other independent groups, and 11% express no particular preference. Among all the respondents, almost 44% say they’re not sure which group they prefer more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: Which political groups (including Reformists, Principalist, and Moderates,) do you tend to lean toward? Which is to say, with which of these group’s idea does you most agree?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, these numbers aren’t necessarily an indication that reformists will enjoy a majority in the new parliament. Parliamentary composition depends on an intricate set of electoral mechanisms, many of which have worked to secure seats for the Principalists due to partisan disqualification of many Reformist candidates. Among 290 total seats, Reformists are fielding 140 dedicated candidates and support another 9 who are not formally affiliated with them but to some extent share party values.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Assessment of the Level of Freedom of the Election&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-six percent of Iranians believe that the parliamentary election will be completely free, and 46% say the election would be somewhat free. Moreover, 13% register the opinion that the election will be a little free or not free at all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: In your opinion to what extent will the coming parliamentary elections be free? Which is to say, completely free, somewhat free, or not free at all.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a separate query, IPOS asks about the preliminary qualification process for candidates: namely, whether or not candidates should stand to a popular vote regardless of the determinations of the Guardian Council. According to the results, 43% believe that the Guardian Council should approve candidate qualifications prior to the election. On the other hand, 41% say that the electorate should have final say in selecting representatives.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: What do you think about the preliminary qualification process for candidates? Some say the Guardian Council should approve candidate qualifications prior to elections. Others maintain the Guardian Council should not have such authority on behalf of people, and that the electorate should have final say in selecting representatives. Which point of view do you agree with?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart7.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;President Rouhani Job Approval: 67%&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;President Rouhani’s job approval is at the highest level since iPOS started assessing it on a quarterly basis. Sixty-seven percent of Iranians presently say that they approve of the job Mr. Rouhani is doing as president, almost 13 percentage points more than in July 2015. Eighteen percent disapprove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: To date, president Rouhani has been sitting in power for nearly two and a half years.  Generally speaking, do you approve or disapprove of the way Mr. Rouhani is handling his job as President?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart8.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPOS typically ask respondents how would they assess the president’s performance on a scale of 0 to 20. His score in February 2016 stands at 14.9, the highest score iPOS has assessed since our inaugural poll in November 2014. In August 2015, his score was 13.9.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: On a scale of 0 to 20, how would you assess the President’s performance?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart9.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Parliament Job Approval: 28% / Assembly of Experts Job Approval: 40%&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A majority of Iranians (43%) disapprove of the way that the parliament is doing its job. Only 28% approve of the job being done by parliament and 18% believe that the performance of the parliament is middling or average.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: To date, the present parliament has been sitting for nearly four years. Generally speaking, do you approve or disapprove of the way parliament is handling its job?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart10.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPOS also asked respondents to assess their own representatives in parliament. According to the results, 48% disapprove (somewhat dissatisfied or completely dissatisfied) of the job being done by their member. Thirty percent believe that their own representative is doing well (somewhat satisfied or completely satisfied). Thirteen percent say their own representative is performing in an average or middling fashion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: How about your own representative? Do you approve or disapprove the way he/she is handling his/her job?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart11.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents were also asked about their assessment of the performance of the Assembly of Experts. Results indicate that 40% of the respondents approve of the job being done by the Assembly of Experts and 15% disapprove. Curiously, a conspicuous 36% indicate that they have no sense at all of the Assembly’s performance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: As you may be aware, the term of the present Assembly of Experts has lasted the last nine years. Generally speaking, do you approve or disapprove of the way the Assembly is handling its job?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart12.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Across distinct questions, iPOS asked respondents about their level of familiarity with the responsibilities of the Assembly of Experts and its chairman. Only 38% of respondents could define at least one of the responsibilities of the Assembly of Experts (including supervision of the Supreme Leader, selection of the Supreme Leader, and his dismissal). Forty-seven percent of respondents answered outright that they weren’t familiar with the Assembly’s role, and another 15% registered incorrect guesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: Do you know what the main responsibilities of the Assembly of Experts?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart13.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart13&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, only 10% could accurately name the chairman of the Assembly. Nearly 70% claimed outright not to know, and almost 20% registered incorrect guesses. Fifty-one percent of respondents could correctly name the speaker of parliament, however.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: Can you identify the present speaker of the Assembly of Experts?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart14.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart14&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: Can you also identify the present speaker of parliament?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart15.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart15&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Candidate Choice Criteria: 90% Value Great Expertise, While Only 21 % Place Emphasis on Ethnic Background&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The aggregate result of respondents’ assessments of various candidate choice criteria shows that having great expertise and being religious are viewed as the most important qualities in respondents’ voting decisions (90% and 87% respectively) whereas sharing the respondent’s ethnicity and being young were the least important factors (21% and 40% respectively).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: People usually take various criteria into consideration when choosing among candidates. I’ll now read a few sentences regarding such criteria. Please tell me how important each of the following criteria is to you in your voting decision which is to say very important, somewhat important, or not at all important.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart16.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart16&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Iran vs. Saudi Arabia&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iranians are possessed of different opinions when it comes to the matter of international disagreement between Iran and Saudi Arabia. Forty-seven percent of Iranians believe that Iran should deal with Saudi trespasses with a firm hand, suggesting such means as resistance, breaking diplomatic relationships, and even declaring war at rates of 28%, 13% and 6% respectively. Twenty-four percent prefer peace talks or negotiation, and 6% say Iran should not send pilgrims to the Hajj religious ceremony within Saudi borders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Question: For the final question we’ll turn our attention to recent disagreements between Iran and Saudi Arabia. In your opinion how should Iran react to recent Saudi actions?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/elections-feb-16/chart17.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart17&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Telephone interviews (cellphone and landline) were conducted from February 12 -20, 2015, with a random sample of 1,184 Iranians aged 18 and older living in Iran.  Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province.  Provinces have been categorized into three groups based on their human development index (HDI).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the sample, there is a 95 percent confidence that the margin of sampling error is between ± 2.85 and ± 3.17 percentage points, depending on the number of respondents for each question.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nine demographic variables including gender, age, province of residence, location (urban or rural), education, language, ethnicity, religion, and residential situation have been considered in this poll.  Results are weighted by gender, age and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from demographic variables, two ground variables (communication variables) were used to gauge respondents’ level of awareness concerning the matter of corruption:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;To what extent did they keep up with election news&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What media channels did they use to acquire such information&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Remarks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following complicating factors should be noted regarding the level of participation in the election:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous surveys suggest people generally exaggerate in their self-reporting of voting intentions. In elections around the world (including the United States) the level of participation registered in polls is usually greater than the empirical turnout on election day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To have a better sense of who will actually cast ballots, we asked about the respondent’s awareness of the date of the election. According to the results, sixty-nine percent of Iranians are aware of the parliamentary election date (i.e., they’re able to name the exact date or, more generally, month in which the election is going to happen). The level of awareness of the Assembly of Expert’s election is lower at 46 percent.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our polling period concluded on February 20th, six days before the election day. We assume that responses regarding the level of awareness would become more accurate as election day drew near. We assume moreover that people tend to be more likely to report that they’ll take part in the elections they nearer they are to election day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Iran doesn’t have a registration-based voting system and analysis of likely voters vs. registered voters is thus not possible. For this reason, we normally assume that the empirical participation level will be less than numbers indicated by poll respondents. Because our poll did not extent through the final week of the election period, however, we assume, based on past trends, the percentage of the respondents who say that they will “definitely vote” could increase to 80%, and the level of awareness of the election date to 70% in the final days leading up to election day. Based on these two numbers, our projection of the turnout rate in the next election hovers between 70% and 80%.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Both elections (parliament and Assembly of Experts) are held simultaneously. We thus assume that voters who show up to cast a ballot for their parliamentary representative will also vote in the Assembly of Experts contest as a matter of course. However, we predict that the level of participation in the Assembly of Experts election will be less overall than that of the parliamentary election.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In light of criteria detailed above, iPOS anticipates that the turnout rate will be more than 70% and less than 80%. The last time Iran enjoyed such a massive participation in a parliamentary election was twenty years ago in 1996, with 71 percent turnout.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Further Background&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next election for Iran’s parliament and Assembly of Experts will be held February 26, 2016. The elections are the first of their kind to follow President Hassan Rouhani’s June 2013 victory in the presidential contest and the subsequent conclusion and implementation of the P5+1 nuclear deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two main political factions face off in both contests. The Reformist and Moderate coalition (including president Rouhani and two former presidents, Mr. Khatami and Mr. Hashemi) represent one side. On the other side, the Principalists and their political icons such as Mr. Hadad Adel (former speaker of the parliament) and three high-ranking clerks, including Mr. Janati (head of the Guardian Council), Mr. Yazdi (chairman of the Assembly of Experts) and Mr. Mesbah-Yazdi (spiritual leader of the Iranian hardliners) have built their own alliance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPos conducted this poll to evaluate the political atmosphere of Iran heading into the election, thus assessing a number of important factors in both elections such as level of participation, political group affiliation, general popular awareness of the elections, the electorate’s criteria in choosing their candidates, and job approval ratings of the president, parliament, and Assembly of Experts. Moreover, since any election in Iran is proceeded by debate about the level of political freedom (specifically in regards to the Guardian Council’s “prequalification” process) we posed some questions to gauge average Iranians’ views on such matters.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2016 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/02/24/elections/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/02/24/elections/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Banks are Most Corrupt Institutions in Iran; Municipal Governments, Judiciary and Police Follow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In its latest survey, IPOS analyzed public understandings of the nature and quantity of corruption in Iran, as well as the Iranian people&#39;s assessments of institutions affected by corruption and anti-corruption efforts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to this survey, banks are viewed as having the highest levels of corruption among 14 other kinds of institutions. Seventy-seven percent of Iranians believe that banks are corrupted either a great deal, a lot, or somewhat. Moreover, a considerable majority of Iranians (71%) say the corruption has become definitive in the country. In addition, ninety-six percent of Iranians are of the opinion that appropriate or harsh punishment more than any other measure would have a mitigating effect, tending to decrease corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/ipos-corruption-in-iran-january-2016.pdf&quot;&gt;Full results are available here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Institutions Judged to be Corrupt&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;People’s evaluations of corruption rates in various institutions show that people generally deem banks to be the most corrupt (77%) among 14 other institutions assessed in this survey. After banks, in descending order, come municipalities (63%), the judiciary system (63%), and police (55%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the other side, environmental organizations are esteemed as the least corrupt institutions. Only 22% of respondents believe that such bodies are corrupted a great deal, a lot, or somewhat.  After environment organizations, the Bonyad-e- Mostazafin and the Revolutionary Guards are judged the least corrupted, at 24% and 30% respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Institutions Affected by Corruption in Varying Degrees (%) &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; A Great Deal &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; A Lot &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Somewhat &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; A Little &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Very Little, Not at All &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; I Don’t Know &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Banks                                                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 27           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 30    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 20       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 9        &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6                       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Local Governing Councils                                   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 24           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 26    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 13       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 18       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 6                       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 13           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Courts &amp;amp; Justice Department                                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 26           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 24    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 13       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 16       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 10           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Police                                                     &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 13           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 21    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 20       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 19       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 18                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 9            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Org. for Registration &amp;amp; Properties                         &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 15           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 24    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 15       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 15       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 10                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 21           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Health System &amp;amp; Hospitals                                  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 19    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 21       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 27       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 18                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Local Governing Councils                                   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 13           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 23    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 14       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 17       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 12                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 21           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Traffic Police                                             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 12           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 19    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 17       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 26       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 18                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Universities                                               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 18    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 20       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 22       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 14                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 18           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Komiteh-e Emdad                                            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 9            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 12       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 24       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 25                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 19           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Educational System &amp;amp; Schools                               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 10    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 16       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 33       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 29                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Revolutionary Guard                                        &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 9            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 10    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 20       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 26                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 24           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Bonyad-e Mostazafan                                        &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 5            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 7     &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 23       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 21                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 33           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Department of Environment                                  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 8     &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 30       &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 24                      &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 23           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Pervasive Corruption in Iran&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A considerable majority of Iranians (71%) believe that corruption has become definitive in the country. Only 15% think that corruption has not become epidemic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Analysis of responses based on demographic variables demonstrates that city dwellers are in a meaningful way more likely to believe in the pervasiveness of corruption (84%); those in rural areas are conversely less likely to believe that it’s epidemic (78%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Moreover, respondents who express that they keep up with news regarding corruption either a lot or a great deal are more likely to believe that corruption is pervasive (89%) than those who say that they either don’t at all follow corruption-related news, or follow it only a little (those who either reported that they had no opinion and were not informed or registered otherwise vague responses were set aside).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Assessment of Corruption: Corruption Trends (Past vs. Future)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pessimistic respondents outnumbered optimists by nearly four to one. Sixty-eight percent of Iranians are convinced that corruption has increased in the last five years, and around 17% think that it has decreased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the question of the likelihood of corruption decreasing in the coming five years is posed, the gap between optimists and pessimists narrows to 33% and 35% respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Older generations are more optimistic about the future than younger generations&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Individuals below 45 years of age and those 45 and above differently evaluate future rates of corruption. The younger cohort tends to pessimism, believing that corruption will worsen in the next five years, whereas those greater than 45 years of age are more optimistic, believing that the rate of corruption will improve (those who either reported that they had no opinion and were not informed or registered otherwise vague responses were set aside).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart7.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Future Corruption Trends by News Source&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A meaningful relationship has been established between media channels used for pursuing information regarding corruption and respondents’ appraisal of corruption trends for the next five years. Thus respondents who obtain such news through the internet, satellite networks, and word of mouth believe that the corruption situation will get worse in the coming five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those who follow news on Iranian state media and users of print media are convinced that the corruption situation will either improve or at least not change in the coming five years (those who either reported that they had no opinion and were not informed or have otherwise vague responses are set aside).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart8.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Influence of Nuclear Agreement on Attention to Anti-Corruption Efforts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In light of nuclear agreement between Iran and the West, 54% of Iranians believe that officials will pay greater attention to combatting corruption.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart9.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Factors Mitigation Corruption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to understand people’s assessments of the role of mitigating corruption, eight different possible measures were posed to respondents. They were then asked to express the level of their agreement with whether or not each measure would have a corruption-mitigating role.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart10.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Noting the findings among those who responded to these questions, it will be observed that respondents believe that appropriate or harsh punishments (96%) more than any other component would have a mitigating effect, tending to decrease corruption. Ethics and the enforcement of regulations assume respective positions behind punishment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrarily, respondents believe that state non-intervention would not tend to curtail corruption (at 32% agreement and 68% disagreement.) State financial decentralization (meaning not concentrating all income into the state’s pockets) and media surveillance occupy the following ranks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Rate of Corruption&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents were asked to score the level of corruption in society on a scale of 1 to 100. Average appraisals of corruption in the country come in at 60 (mean). The median score is also 60, meaning that half of the respondents give a score more than 60 for the level of corruption in the country and the other half give scores less than 60. The mode (most frequent number) is 50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the table below, almost 30% of the respondents gave scores between 75 and 100 for the level of corruption. Just 10 gave a score less than 25.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Corruption Score (Ordinal) &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; %    &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1 to 25                    &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 9.6  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 26 to 50                   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 37   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 51 to 75                   &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 24.6 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 76 to 100                  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 28.8 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Central Tendency &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;    &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Mean             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 60 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Median           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 60 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Mode             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 50 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Comparing Rate of Corruption to Other Countries&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On a scale of 1 to 150, respondents were asked to rank Iran in terms of corruption among the world’s 150 other countries. According to the average appraisal, Iran ranked the 80th most corrupt country of 150. The median score is 75, meaning that half of the respondents gave a rank of more than 75 and the other half gave a rank of less than 75. The mode (most frequent number) is 100. Fourteen percent of respondents ranked Iran as the 100th most corrupt country in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the most recent report of the International Transparency Organization (2014,) Iran was given a score equivalent to 27 (on a scale of 100) with regard to corruption. It was also ranked 136th in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Comparative  Corruption Rank (vis-à-vis Other Countries) &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; %  &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 1 to 10                                                  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 13 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 11 to 50                                                 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 21 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 51 to 100                                                &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 36 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 101 to 140                                               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 17 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 141 to 150                                               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 13 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Central Tendency &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;     &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Mean             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 80  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Median           &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 75  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Mode             &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 100 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;A Majority of Iranians Do Not Follow Corruption-Related News&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generally speaking, Iranians do not follow news regarding corruption (68% of respondents said that they either don’t at all follow corruption-related news, or follow it little). Only 14% say that they follow such news “a lot.” This result is consonant with the findings of other IPOS polls which have, in the past, gauged general trends in Iranian’s keeping up with news and current affairs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt; Degree of Following Corruption News &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt; %  &lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; A Great Deal                        &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 4  &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; A Lot                               &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 10 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Somewhat                            &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 18 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Little                              &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 14 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Very Little                         &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 16 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt; Never at All                        &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt; 38 &lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Iran’s National Radio &amp;amp; TV is the Primary Source for Corruption News&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Among people who follow corruption-related news, Iran’s National Radio &amp;amp; TV (state media) is the primary source for corruption news (35%.) Informal word-of-mouth networks come in afterwards at 27%, the internet at 19%, print journalism at 12%, and satellite networks at 6%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/corruption-jan-16/chart12.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews (cellphone and landline) conducted on September 26, 2015 to October 08, 2015, with a random sample of 1548 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who are currently residing in Iran.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province. Provinces have been categorized into three groups based on their human development index (HDI).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is between ± 2.49 and ± 3.47 percentage points, depending on the number of respondents for each question&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rates of respondent candor and reliability were appraised by experienced interviewers. 48 persons found to be lacking in these areas were removed from the sample.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nine demographic variables including gender, age, province of residence, location (urban or rural), education, language, ethnicity, religion, and residential situation have been considered in this poll. Results are weighted by gender, age and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Aside from demographic variables, two ground variables (communication variables) were used to gauge respondents’ level of awareness concerning the matter of corruption:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first: to what extent did they keep up with news pertaining to official and economic corruption (i.e. embezzlement, favoritism, and the like?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The second: What media channels did they use to acquire such information?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2016 02:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/01/20/corruption/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2016/01/20/corruption/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Nuclear Deal: 76 percent Approve, 3 Percent Disapprove</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a recent IPOS survey, Iranians overwhelmingly favor a nuclear deal with the West on the terms of the “Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action”. Seventy-six percent approve of such a plan while three percent disapprove. A poll last May showed that 63% answered affirmatively to the question “Do you support a deal between Iran and the West?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July of 2015 Iran and Western powers announced that that they had come to an agreement regarding Iran’s nuclear program. A poll conducted by iPOS in August 2015 suggests that a majority of Iranians favor a nuclear deal with the West and the so called “Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action”. Seventy-six percent approve of such a plan while three percent disapprove. Nine percent of Iranians say they would approve a deal if it is not against Iran’s national interest and 12% register other alternatives such as “I don’t know” or “I have no idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;As you may know, Iran and the West announced that they had come to agreement regarding the nuclear program. When we talk to people some say they favor a deal, some say not. What do you think?  Would you say you favor a deal between Iran and the West or not?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Approval of a Deal Based on Age&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marked differences are apparent across age cohorts, with older Iranians aged more than 45 being more likely to say they approve of a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approval of a deal does not vary in a statistically significant way when analyzed according to other variables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Approval of a Deal Based on Ethnicity&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The approval of a deal does not vary in a statistically significant way when analyzed according to other variables such as gender, educational level, location, ethnicity, or religion. Among the ethnic groups, however, Iranian Kurds are more likely to say they approve of a deal than the population generally (86% of Iranian Kurds approve a deal). Rates of approval of a deal are 80% and 79% among Iranian Arabs and Baluchs respectively. Among Lurs, Persian, and Turks the approval of a deal stands at 73%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chartA.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Approval of a Deal Based on Religion&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iranian Sunnis are more likely to say they approve of a deal (82%). The rate of approval is 75% among Iranian Shias.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chartB.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Approval of a Deal Based on Other Parameters&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chart7.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-sept-15/chart8.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews conducted on August 22 to 24, 2015, with a random sample of 654 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who are currently residing in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are weighted by gender, age and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is ± 3.8 percentage points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 15 Sep 2015 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/09/15/nuclear-deal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/09/15/nuclear-deal/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>August 2015: Rohani’s Job Approval Improves</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;President Rohani’s job approval rating is better now than it was in May 2015. Fifty-four percent of Iranians say they approve of the job Mr. Rohani’s performance as president, a significant increase over the past three months. Twenty-two percent disapprove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Rohani&#39;s Job Performance Ratings: August, 2015&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the poll conducted by iPOS in August 2015, 39% of Iranians say they &quot;approve&quot; of the way Mr. Rohani is handling his job as president, while 15% say they &quot;somewhat approve&quot;. At the critical end of the five-point spectrum, 20% express their &quot;dissatisfaction&quot; with Mr. Rohani’s performance, and 4% say they are &quot;somewhat dissatisfied&quot; with how Mr.Rohani is handling his job. Seventeen percent have a neutral view (considered as an average favorability rating for purposes of this poll), and another 5% register other options such as &quot;I have no idea&quot;, &quot;not interested in this topic&quot;, and &quot;I don’t know&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-aug-15/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Rohani Job Performance Ratings Based on Gender, Age, Educational Level and Location&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-aug-15/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-aug-15/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-aug-15/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-aug-15/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews conducted on August 22 to 24, 2015, with a random sample of 654 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who are currently residing in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are weighted by gender, age and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is ± 3.8 percentage points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Remark:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presidential job approval is an important indicator of how reformists, moderates, and conservatives might perform in the upcoming 2015 parliamentary elections and 2016 presidential elections. iPOS tracks the presidential job approval rating among all Iranian adults aged 18 and older on a quarterly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2015 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/09/01/rouhani-job-approval/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/09/01/rouhani-job-approval/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Iranians Support Nuclear Deal, Remain Skeptical of the West and Want Normalization of Iran-U.S. Relations</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Ahead of a June 31 deadline for negotiations over Iran’s nuclear program, a poll conducted by iPOS in May 2015 suggests that a majority of Iranians favor a nuclear deal with the West (63%) while two-thirds of Iranians remain skeptical about the prospect of a final deal and report less trust in the U.S. and other Western countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;iPOS also found that 52% of Iranians answered affirmatively to the following prompt: “If Iran and the West reach a nuclear deal, would  you agree or disagree with a normalization of relations between Iran and the US?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Nuclear Deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A majority of Iranians (63%) approve of a deal being reached between Iran and the West, compared to just 9% who disapprove. Twelve percent of Iranians say they would approve a deal if it is not against Iran’s national interest and 16% register other alternatives such as “I don’t know” or “I have no idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A poll last November conducted by iPOS showed that 65% answered the same question affirmatively, with 11% opposing such a proposition and 9% saying that they would support a deal conditionally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents were markedly split by their geographical location and age group. Those who were located in an urban area were more likely to approve a deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Prospect of a Final Deal&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just one-third of Iranians trust the U.S. and the West to keep their promises about their commitments regarding Iran’s nuclear program. When people were asked whether they trust the U.S. and the West, just nine percent say they mostly trusted them and 23% said that they trust them somewhat. Fifteen percent report that they will never trust the U.S. and the West at all and 23% believe there is a very low chance for a long-term commitment beyond a nuclear deal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marked differences are apparent across age cohorts, with younger Iranians aged 45 and less more likely to say they trust the U.S and the West.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart7.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‫Women are more likely than men to express distrust of the U.S and the West in keeping their promises‬.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart8.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Iran-U.S Relations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those surveyed were asked whether they favor or oppose normalization of Iran-U.S. relations, in the event that Iran and the West reach a nuclear deal. Fifty-two percent of Iranians say they support such a normalization, while 20% oppose. Eleven percent of Iranians say they support a normalization of Iran-U.S relation if it would not oppose Iran’s national interest and on the condition that the United States would not intervene in Iran’s domestic issues. Seventeen percent register other options like “I don’t know” and “I have no idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart9.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data analysis indicated that approval of the normalization of Iran-U.S. relations is varies in a statistically significant way between respondents with and without higher education.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/nuclear-deal-june-15/chart10.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews conducted from May 27 to 29, 2015, with a random sample of 680 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who are currently residing in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are weighted by gender, age and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is ± 3.8 percentage points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Persian speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jun 2015 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/06/23/nuclear-deal/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/06/23/nuclear-deal/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Iranians’ Views on the Green Movement Legacy</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According the poll conducted by iPOS in June 2015 to study the legacy of the six-year-old Green Movement (the movement that arose after the controversial 2009 presidential election), 59% of Iranians say that there was no fraud in the proceedings while 19% still accuse the government of fraudulent conduct. Twenty-two percent register alternative responses such as “I don’t know”, “I have no idea,” or other options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public is also split over whether or not it is appropriate for demonstrators to protest in the streets. Thirty-nine percent approve of such demonstrations, while 40% disapprove. When people were asked whether they favored or opposed the way police react to street protests, 40% say the police reaction is justified, while 35% say it’s not justified.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The iPOS findings regarding the poll are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Legitimacy of the 2009 Presidential Election&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fifty-nine percent of Iranians say that there was no fraud in election, while 19% still view the government as culpable for what they regarded as a fraudulent election. Twenty-two percent register alternative responses such as “I don’t know”, “I have no idea,” or other options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents were markedly split by their level of education, location (urban or rural areas) and by the Human Development Index (HDI), level of the provinces in which they reside. Those respondents who had a higher level of education, were located in an urban area, or resided in a province with a higher HDI were more likely to say there was a fraud in 2009 presidential election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to this poll, 89% of respondents aged 24 or more say they voted in the 2009 presidential election, very close to the 85% official voter turnout.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;The Right to Demonstrate&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The public is split over whether or not it is appropriate for demonstrators to protest in the streets. Thirty-nine percent approve of such protests, while 40% disapprove. Five percent say it depends on laws and regulations and 4% believe it would be better if protestors specifically did not gather in the streets. Twelve percent register alternative options including “I don’t know” and “I have no idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart7.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When respondents were disaggregated by demographic variables (age, gender, location, and HDI of the province in which they reside), those respondents who have a higher level of education and are located in urban areas are more likely to support the street protests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart8.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart8&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart9.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart9&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Police Reaction&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When respondents were asked about whether they favored or opposed the way Police react to street protests, 40% say the police reaction is justified, while 35% say it’s not justified. Two percent believe it depends on laws and regulations and 23% register “I don’t know,”  “I have no idea.” or other options.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart10.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart10&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The analysis of data indicated that approval of the right to demonstrate was statistically significantly different among those who are located in urban areas and have higher educational levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart11.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart11&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart12.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart12&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Protester Identity&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A majority of Iranians say those who protested on the streets after the 2009 presidential election were ordinary people and students (youth,) assessed at 41% and 21% respectively. On the other hand, just 6 percent believe that the protesters had been guided by foreign countries or that they had a plan to subvert the regime. Nine percent say they were rich people and 23% register other options such as “I don’t know” and “I have no idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart13.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart13&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents to this question were markedly split by their gender, level of education and location (urban or rural areas).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart14.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart14&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart15.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart15&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart16.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart16&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Green Movement vs Sedition&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the presidential election in 2009, there was antagonism between the government and its opponents. Opponents named themselves the Green Movement, but the government viewed their actions as intrigue, labeling the movement sedition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Those surveyed were asked which of these two names better describes what happened after the election. Respondents are split evenly, 28% for each side. Nine percent say neither of these wordings is accurate and 4% believe that what happened in 2009 after the election can be legitimately described as both. Thirty-one percent register other options such as “I don’t know” or “I have no idea.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart17.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart17&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Future of the Green Movement Leaders: Freedom, Trial or House Arrest&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iranian opposition leaders Mirhosein Mousavi and Mehdi Karoubi have been under house arrest since February 2011. Only 31% of respondents in this survey knew this fact.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another disputed subject regarding the 2009 presidential election is whether or not the Green Movement leaders in fact deserve to be under house arrest. Some say that because they have not been charged with any crime under Iranian law, the government should free them immediately. Some believe they should face prosecution for their actions after the election, that they have a right to defend themselves publicly, and that any charges against them should be proven in a court of law. The last option is house arrest without any charges, which has been favored by the government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poll conductors asked which of these three options would be the best-case scenario in the view of the respondents (those who previously were not aware of the current situation of green movement leaders were informed of the fact of their house arrest before being asked this secondary question.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty-one percent believe that the government should free the leaders immediately. Nineteen percent say Green Movement leaders should be asked to present evidence of their fraud allegations in a court of law. Eight percent suggest that everything should be dependent on law, and just 6 percent think the house arrest is the best option.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart18.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart18&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Marked differences are apparent across age cohorts, with those who are age 45 and older more likely to say the government has to free the leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Possibility of Demonstrations after the 2013 Election&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents were asked what should have happened if the 2013 presidential election results varied greatly from what was expected. To wit: in such a case, should people once more go to the streets and protest?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forty-eight percent of respondents said no, 24% said yes (or maybe) and 25% register other options like “I have no idea” or “I don’t know.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/green-movement/chart19.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart19&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews conducted from June 6 to 12, 2015 with a randomly selected sample of 1048 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who are currently residing in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents on landlines and cellular phones representing every province.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is ± 3 percentage points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are weighted by gender, age and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Persian speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDI (Human Development Index) is a composite statistical index measuring well-being across a number of different variables such as education, income, and health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;This poll was conducted for Iranwire.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2015 03:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/06/22/green-movement/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/06/22/green-movement/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rohani’s Job Approval Stands at 48%</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;President Rohani’s job approval rating stands at 48%, similar to his 49% reading on Feb. 2015, but down from 58% last winter. Disapproval inched up 4 points since Feb. 2015 from 29 to 33 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the poll conducted by iPOS in May 2015, 37% of Iranians say they &quot;approve&quot; of the way Mr. Rohani is handling his job as president, while 11% say they &quot;somewhat approve&quot;. At the critical end of the five-point spectrum, 28% express their &quot;dissatisfaction&quot; with Mr. Rohani’s performance, and 5% say they are &quot;somewhat dissatisfied&quot; with how Mr. Rohani is handling his job. Fifteen percent have a neutral view (considered as an average favorability rating for purposes of this poll), and another 7% register other options such as &quot;I have no idea&quot;, &quot;not interested in this topic&quot;, and &quot;I don’t know&quot;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-may-15/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Rohani Job Performance Ratings Based on Gender, Age, Educational Level and Location&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president’s job approval rating does not vary in a statistically significant way when analyzed according to the gender, educational level and location of respondents. Marked differences are apparent across age cohorts, with 70% of those aged 59 or more approving of Mr. Rohani’s job performance, 49% for ages 45-59, 40% for ages 30-44 and 47% for ages 18-29. Mr. Rohani’s favorability is still high among elderly Iranians, but his approval has dropped among all other age cohorts since Feb 2015.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-may-15/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-may-15/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-may-15/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/rouhani-job-approval-may-15/chart6.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart6&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews conducted on May 27 to 29 2015, with a random sample of 680 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who are currently residing in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents from every province.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are weighted by gender, age and location (urban vs. rural areas) based on the Iranian national census of 2011.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is ± 3.8 percentage points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;


&lt;h4&gt;Remark:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Presidential job approval is an important indicator of how reformists, moderates, and conservatives might perform in the upcoming 2014 parliamentary elections and 2016 presidential elections. iPOS tracks the presidential job approval rating among all Iranian adults aged 18 and older on a quarterly basis.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/06/10/rouhani-job-approval/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/06/10/rouhani-job-approval/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Among Iranians, 42% Support Voluntary Hijab while 53% Oppose</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to a poll conducted by IPOS, 42% of Iranians say that wearing an Islamic hijab should be optional for women, while 38% believe it to be obligatory for religious reasons and another 15% maintain that it should be mandatory on strictly legal grounds. Five percent register other responses such as “I don’t know”, “I have no idea” and “I am not interested in this topic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents were markedly split by their level of education. A full 51% percent of those with a university degree say that wearing the Hijab should be voluntary. By contrast, 60% of those without university degrees support an obligatory hijab policy, either on religious or legal grounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/hejab/chart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart2&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents residing in provinces with a higher Human Development Index are more likely to prefer elective hijab wearing. The percentage of respondents supporting mandatory hijabs, is significantly higher in provinces with a low Human Development Index.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/hejab/chart5.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart5&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Respondents’ views regarding the hijab do not vary in a statistically significant way when analyzed according to either gender or age. However, women were slightly more inclined to support compulsory hijabs than men (58% to 55%). Forty-eight percent of those ages 18 to 29 support voluntary hijabs, more than any other age group polled.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/hejab/chart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart3&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/en/assets/posts/hejab/chart4.png&quot; alt=&quot;chart4&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4&gt;Survey Methods:&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Results are based on telephone interviews conducted from June 7 to 9, 2015, with a randomly selected sample of 600 Iranian adults aged 18 and older who are currently residing in Iran.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The iPOS proportional two-stage sample includes respondents on landlines and cellular phones representing every province.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Based on the sample, it can be stated with 95% confidence that the margin of sampling error is ± 4 percentage points.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Native Farsi speakers conducted the interviews during daylight hours in Iran. Interviewers were trained prior to conducting the poll.
Remarks&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HDI (Human Development Index) is a composite statistical index measuring the well-being across a number of different variables such as education, income, and health.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Data analysis incorporating such variables as educational level, location, gender and age makes use only of definitive affirmative or negative responses; i.e., iPOS removes from this data set all respondents who registered options such as “I don’t know”, “I have no ides” and “I am not interested in this topic”.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2015 04:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/03/18/hejab/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://www.ipos.me/en/polls/2015/03/18/hejab/</guid>
        
        
        <category>polls</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
